(Supported by NRTA's Online Audiovisual
Quality Creation & Distribution Project)
♪Black hair twines around bone♪
♪Night dew cold♪
♪Bronze mirror cracks
through three lifetimes♪
♪Shines on the sleepless♪
♪Yunmeng Marsh ebbs and flows♪
♪Vows sink deep♪
♪White-hair curse turns to snow♪
♪Covering the realm♪
=Reunion Across Time=
=Episode 2=
(Shaman Clan Register)
What's wrong?
I can't read.
(Shaman Clan Register)
So what if I can't read?
I grew up in the Shaman Clan.
Of course I only know
Shaman Clan script.
What's so funny?
(What a loving couple.)
(Why must they be torn apart?)
She's your sweetheart?
I don't have a sweetheart.
What did she just say?
"Tear them apart"?
You let that girl down.
I didn't.
What a jerk.
Why is heaven so unfair to me,
making me watch others
be all lovey-dovey?
We're not!
If that's the case,
I'll just have to
kill you.
What does that have to do with me?
How vulgar.
So you're a shamaness.
It seems you can bear
my primordial spirit.
Come with me.
(If you want to save your lover,)
(come find me.)
My Grand Shaman ambitions...
Song Ziyuan.
Don't come closer.
For your lover,
you'd brave danger all alone.
How touching.
Are lovers
all you ever think about?
Moonflower?
No wonder.
I heard your kind
must cling to trees to grow.
Your kind falls hardest in love.
But my beloved locust tree's body
is already dead.
Plants like us have fragile bodies.
If we had human bodies,
we wouldn't die so easily.
So,
let me have your body.
So it was you
searching the city all along
for a body to house your spirit.
That's why those people
couldn't bear your spirit
and mutated and died.
They were ordinary people.
But you're different.
You're a shamaness.
You can do it.
Let him down now!
No.
He'll soon be my beloved locust tree.
Your blood can hurt her.
How did you know
my blood could hurt her?
Your blood can actually hurt me?
Impressive.
Help me!
My beloved locust tree,
As you live, I live.
If you die, I'll follow.
My beloved locust tree...
Song Ziyuan,
why did you save me?
Weren't you going to kill me?
How did you know
my blood could hurt her?
Tell me!
I never thought...
the last time...
would end like this...
I...
Song Ziyuan,
what do you mean, last time?
You...
Song Ziyuan!
(Why?)
(Why does my heart ache so much?)
What on earth is going on?
Song Ziyuan,
who are you really?
I need to know everything.
I'm a shamaness.
I can call your soul back.
Song Ziyuan,
I'm bringing you back to life.
(Scorching sun burns its feathers.)
(Drifting sands bury the spirit altar.)
(Xuanming Soul-Freezing Banner.)
(Rivers chill the bones.)
(Soul...)
(Return!)
Song Ziyuan, wake up.
Wake up.
No.
Something's wrong.
How can this be?
Everyone has
three souls and seven spirits.
Why do you only have
a wisp of your soul left?
There's no other way.
I'll have to use this.
I trade my soul
for the return of yours.
Didn't I die?
This is...
It's my corpse.
Then I'm...
a spirit now?
Could it be
that Chu Li and I...
We did it.
You're
Chu Li?
Song Ziyuan now?
♪Night rain falls in the courtyard,
shining on mortal partings♪
♪Strangers meet again,
past lives gleam in endless hues♪
♪A sharp arrow pierces memory♪
♪Longing spreads like dye♪
♪Beaded curtains
keep love and hate apart♪
♪Through boundless grief,
love remains hard to sever♪
♪A past bond, a parting dream;
when cold ends, purest joy remains♪
♪That year,
pear blossoms, verse, and laughter♪
♪One night, snow fell in wild flurries♪
♪All perfection in this world
hides regret♪
♪A drop of heart's blood seals love♪
♪No more longing enters dreams♪
♪When all turns to mist,
may you and I be safe forever♪
♪Through boundless grief,
love remains hard to sever♪
♪A past bond, a parting dream;
when cold ends, purest joy remains♪